I lost 30, 30 members of my family in two days.
Half of my family is gone.
Every time I talk to my mom, she tries to tell me her final goodbye.
She tells me, I miss you.
I really want to be able to hug you again.
And I tell her, Mama, why are you not strong?
Come on, you're going to hug me again.
And I close the line and I cry for two hours.
I cry at how unjust this world is.
I cry at how the world does not see my humanity.
I cry at how silent the world is.
Not only silent, but complicit in war crimes and massacres
that are being committed against me and my people.
No one is safe in Gaza.
I don't know if my family is going to make it or my friends.
I don't know who's next.
I don't know.
And I don't want to know.
I just wanted to stop.
I just want to wake up from this nightmare.
Everything started on Saturday where I lost my best friend.
The friend that I would call whenever I needed to cry
or whenever I needed to share good news.
Ibrahim and I covered the 2022 aggression on Gaza.
He was the person who would shoot my videos and I was the reporter.
His dream was to become a world-renowned photographer.
In the morning, he texted the group chat of our friends and he said,
the situation is escalating.
I'm going to the office.
So I texted him privately and I said,
Ibrahim, please take care.
My messages didn't go through to Ibrahim and I kept trying to reach him,
but I couldn't.
My colleague said that Ibrahim is missing.
And it's been 10 days and I feel like I just lost him like two minutes ago.
Like, I still don't believe it's real.
I genuinely don't believe it.
I just feel like I'm in a long nightmare and I'm not waking up, you know.
He told me in the 2022 aggression, he told me,
Yara, you're going to be the next Shirin Abu Aqli.
They killed her, but you are Shirin Abu Aqli.
Please don't ever give up journalism.
And he told me, we'll report every aggression side by side.
And I genuinely thought we would, you know, but I didn't know that Israel would just kill him,
just like they did with Shirin Abu Aqli, just like they did with Yasir Murtaja.
Ibrahim became a journalist in the first place because he was so inspired by Yasir's Murtaja
and he wanted to carry on his message.
And I don't know, I never imagined that I'd lose Ibrahim.
He was so young.
He was only 21 years old.
I wish you can give me more time to talk about every single member of my family
who was killed in detail and tell you about their dreams, their ambitions,
what they wanted to be and what they've done in life.
I want to tell you about my eldest uncle.
He had dementia.
He barely remembered anything about his life, but he was always smiling.
He was telling me that he loved me every time he saw me.
I want to tell you about the children.
In my uncle's house only, eight children have been murdered.
Those children, I have so many memories.
I remember them calling me and telling me,
Yara, can you please come for a sleepover?
Yara, we want to do something with you.
I used to love babysitting children, so I used to babysit them whenever I went home.
My cousin, who was murdered yesterday, she was a bride.
She was supposed to get married next month.
She literally prepared everything.
She even picked her wedding dress.
She's been so excited for her wedding and she's been doing it for months and months and everything's gone just like that.
My cousin and her children, her four children, they were Swedish nationals.
They were visiting Gaza and then, you know, they got trapped and they couldn't leave.
They're Swedish nationals.
Yeah.
And they were killed.
How are these terrorists?
How is my family that I grew up with my whole life?
People who taught me how to love.
People who taught me how to live.
And there's so many.
I even feel guilty talking about my family.
I'm not the more than 3,000 Palestinians who have been killed in the last 10 days.
I feel guilty because every single one of the 3,000 was not a number.
Every single one of the 3,000 had the story.
They were journalists.
They were doctors.
They were teachers.
They were dreamers.
They were so much.
They were humans after all.
They were humans.
They had dreams and ambitions.
I don't even have time to grieve my family.
I don't have time to cry or talk about them.
I have to report and I have to work and I have to educate the West.
And I have to tell them why they shouldn't be asking me if I should condemn Hamas or not.
But they should be asking me about Israel and about what Israel is doing.
They shouldn't ask me and dehumanize me when I'm a Palestinian journalist,
not a spokesperson of any political party.
They should ask me about the 30 members of my family who are not militants,
not a group, not part of any group.
They should be asking me these questions.
I just want everyone to know this is not an Israel-Hamas war as Israel portrays it to be.
Let's imagine a world where Hamas does not exist.
Imagine the West Bank.
You know, Hamas is not in control there.
What has been happening in the West Bank?
There's apartheid.
There is military detention of minors.
There is torture.
There is killing of Palestinians every single day.
There is oppression.
There is complete home demolition.
Everything you can imagine they're doing in the West Bank.
So, why are you asking me about Hamas now?
Why are you not asking me about how I didn't see my dad for six years?
And then I went, I saw him, I saw him only for a few months and then he was, he died.
He got really sick and died.
I couldn't see him for six years.
They prevented me from being with my father.
They prevented me from having a normal childhood.
I had to be in therapy for years and years to get over the sound of bombs,
the pictures of murdered children in front of my eyes
and the guilt that I felt that I survived and they didn't.
Why are you not asking me about the thousand Palestinian children
that have been killed in the last 10 days?
Why are you not asking me about how my best friend, a journalist,
marked clearly as press was killed?
Why are you not asking me this?
I'm not a spokesperson for Hamas.
I'm not a part of any political party.
I'm a journalist.
My job is to report on what's happening.
My colleague, Mu'taz Azayzeh, they bombed his house,
killing so many of his family members.
My other colleague, Ali Jadallah, just in the last 10 days,
they've killed his brother, an elderly father.
My boss and mentor, Rushdie Sarraj, was killed as he was in his home on an airstrike.
It was literally targeted the assassination of him because he was a journalist.
They're literally targeting journalists and trying to threaten them.
If you are doing your job, we will kill you.
And this is what Israel has been doing for the last decades
because journalists are the only way for the world to know what's actually happening in Palestine.
I don't remember a day in my life where there was peace.
I was only 8 years old when I witnessed the first aggression on Gaza.
It was in 2008.
And then it was in 2012.
And then it was in 2014.
And only in 2014 that I was able to comprehend what's happening.
Like when I was 8 and I was 12, I didn't really understand death.
I didn't understand white phosphorus or chemical weapons.
I was a child.
The only thing I wanted to do is play and be around my family.
When I was 14, I was in the hospital crying, telling my parents,
I don't believe you're alive.
I was so in shock and in PTSD, post-traumatic distress disorder,
that I genuinely believed my family were completely killed
because of the amount of killings I've seen as a 14-year-old.
If you're a Palestinian living in Gaza and you were born in 2000,
you would have been living through six aggressions by now.
This is not just the first time that Israel decides to completely wipe out
complete neighbourhoods and attack civilians and attack hospitals.
But this is the most barbaric attack that we've seen.
Palestinians in Gaza have not seen one day of peace.
Not one day that my family and I felt safe in our homes.
What is it like to be a Palestinian?
What is it like to grow up in Gaza?
I don't have one answer.
I have millions of answers.
Growing up in Gaza meant that by the age of 14,
I saw literally body parts of people, children being murdered in front of my eyes.
I remember I used to say, if I survive this aggression, if I make it alive,
I'm going to write a book and tell the whole world about what's happening.
And I was only 14 years old.
I didn't realise what was happening to me then.
This is what it's like to grow up in Gaza.
But it's also all the nights that I spent talking to my dad about politics
and how Palestine will be free one day
and how my culture is important
and how I should be committed and steadfast on my land
and how my mum cooks Palestinian food for us
and teaches us the recipes that my grandma made
and that her great-grandma made
and that her great-great-grandma made.
Being Palestinian is so painful
but at the same time, I would never want to be anything but Palestinian
because I know my people, they're the strongest people I've ever met.
They endure so much.
Being Palestinian means that you have friends in the West Bank
but you're unable to meet them or see them.
Being Palestinian means that you're a Muslim or Christian
and want to go pray in Al-Aqsa Mosque or in the Church of Nativity
and you can't just simply because you're from Gaza.
Being Palestinian means that your existence is threatened every single day
and not only that
but that every single day you need to wake up
and convince the world why you're a human
and why your life matters just like the rest of the world.
Being Palestinian is hard.
Being Palestinian is difficult
but being Palestinian is something I will never stop being.
For the first time in my life,
I feel like my voice is being heard
because I'm using my platform, I'm trying to work 24-7
to tell the world what's happening.
And even if news media organizations don't care about Palestinian voices
there are independent news outlets
that are trying every single day
to amplify Palestinian journalist voices
and Double Down News is one of them
so please support them.